<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://escapethedungeon.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://escapethedungeon.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-04-19T19:23:08+10:00</updated><id>https://escapethedungeon.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Escape the Dungeon</title><subtitle>A creative blog that posts singular dungeon rooms filled with challenges to be used in table top role playing games.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Sleeping Beauty (F1-R4)</title><link href="https://escapethedungeon.com/posts/F1-R4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Sleeping Beauty (F1-R4)" /><published>2020-04-20T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-04-20T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://escapethedungeon.com/posts/F1-R4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://escapethedungeon.com/posts/F1-R4/"><![CDATA[<p>A stadium shaped room with partially blackened frescos on the walls. A large grey shape is blocking the eastern side of the room.</p>
<p>On the southern side is an open passageway and the western side are thicken wooden double doors.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/maps/rooms/escapethedungeon-f1-r4-pc.png" alt="The Sleeping Beauty (F1-R4)" /></p>
<hr />
<h2 id="game-master">Game Master</h2>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<h1 id="focus-points">Focus Points</h1>
<p><strong>Beauty The Dragon (F1-R4-CHR01)</strong></p>
<p>A closer look at the hulking figure on the eastern side of the room will reveal it to be a stone statue of a dragon, speckled with gemstones. An easy inspection check will reveal a small gemstone has fallen loose from the statue and lays on the ground.</p>
<p>Adventurers with a medium or higher intelligence will hear the sounds of light snoring inside their mind if they are within 20 feet of the statue. An easy magic check will reveal this dragon is petrified.</p>
<p>The dragon can be brought back to its original form with a scroll/spell of reverse petrification. If this occurs the dragon will talk to the adventures and will only attack if verbally or physically provoked.</p>
<p>If an adventurer has stolen one or more of its gemstones it will know who and will try and convince other adventurers to help it, before attacking the thief.</p>
<p>If the encounter ends peacefully it will give the adventures the Owl Key and teleport out of the room.</p>
<p><strong>Fresco Paintings</strong></p>
<p>A large area of the frescos have been singed by fire some time ago. A medium inspection check will reveal the remaining visuals of the painting to be a tale of a powerful figure and his army venturing into a large entrance in a mountain side.</p>
<p><strong>Exits</strong></p>
<p>To the eastern and western sides of the room are thick wooden double doors, the eastern side is blocked by the dragon statue unless it has moved or killed. On the southern side of the room is an open passageway.</p>
<h1 id="items">Items</h1>
<p><strong>Dragon Gemstones (F1-R4-ITM01)</strong></p>
<p>Fine gemstones of vary colors and shapes speckle the statue, one of the gemstones has fallen loose and lays on the floor. A medium strength check with an appropriate dungoneering tool will be able to pry these stones loose.</p>
<p><em>Note:</em> The dragon will know who stole its gemstones if it is ever unpetrified.</p>
<p><strong>Owl Key (F1-R4-ITM02)</strong></p>
<p>A short bronze key with the symbol of an owl etched into the bow. Using this key on the <a href="/references/intrigues/">Keyhole Panel</a> in <a href="/posts/F1-R3/">The Keyhole Room (F1-R3)</a> will materialise Credius' Bird Cage into the centre of the room.</p>
<p><strong>Credius' Bird Cage (F1-R4-ITM03)</strong></p>
<p>A small golden bird cage with a velvet cushioned floor, a plaque at the bottom of the cage reads &quot;A fancy place to rest.&quot; in fine cursive.</p>
<p>A high magic or lore check will reveal that any small animal that spends a long rest in this cage will return to it when the holder whispers the words on the plaque. If the animal is killed it will return to the cage but its corpse will remain. Upon return the animal must spend an additional long rest in the cage for the effect to take hold again.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<hr />
<h2 id="authors-notes">Authors Notes</h2>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>Starting to mess around with different shaped rooms. These half circles were make with an old Celco Compass but I've ordered a <a href="https://www.officeworks.com.au/shop/officeworks/p/celco-c68-circle-stencil-template-ja0178881">Celco C68 Circle Stencil Template</a> to draw smaller circles better.</p>
<p>Added the first character to the dungeon although there isn't really a way for a new party to interact with it. It is however very close to the Keyhole Panel so if they do end up finding the correct items it should be easy to swing past again.</p>
<p>I couldn't think of a good wizard name of the top of my head so got Credius from <a href="https://www.fantasynamegenerators.com/wizard-names.php">Fantasy Name Generator</a>, maybe they'll be featured more later. I also learned that the handle of a key is called a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lock_and_key">Bow</a>.</p>
<p>Might take a look at the item naming convention to see if I can come up with something clearer.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<hr />
<h2 id="what-this-all-about">What This All About?</h2>
<p>Check out the <a href="/about/"><strong>About</strong></a> page.</p>
<p>Have any ideas or feedback? Tweet or Direct Message me on <a href="https://www.twitter.com/4A616D6573/"><strong>Twitter</strong></a>.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->« The Keyhole Panel (F1-R3)<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="room" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A stadium shaped room with partially blackened frescos on the walls. A large grey shape is blocking the eastern side of the room.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Keyhole Panel (F1-R3)</title><link href="https://escapethedungeon.com/posts/F1-R3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Keyhole Panel (F1-R3)" /><published>2020-04-17T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-04-17T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://escapethedungeon.com/posts/F1-R3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://escapethedungeon.com/posts/F1-R3/"><![CDATA[<p>A wide rectangle room, on the eastern wall above a small stone platform stands a metal panel displaying countless oddly laid out keyholes.</p>
<p>The panel is illuminated by strange purple flames that float in sconces on either side of the panel and around the room.</p>
<p>At the southern end of the room stands a closed metal door with no visible handles.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/maps/rooms/escapethedungeon-f1-r3-pc.png" alt="The Keyhole Panel (F1-R3)" /></p>
<hr />
<h2 id="game-master">Game Master</h2>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<h1 id="focus-points">Focus Points</h1>
<p><strong>Keyhole Panel (F1-R3-INT01)</strong></p>
<p>The panel appears to be made of polished silver and stands 35 feet across and is almost floor to ceiling in height. Worked into the panel are countless keyholes of varying designs and appear to fit different kinds of keys. Above each keyhole is a symbol that has been worked into the silver, these are also of varying style.</p>
<p><em>Note:</em> Keys for this room will be discoverable throughout the dungeon. The post in which a key is presented will list what it unlocks within this room, once used on the panel.</p>
<p><strong>Exits</strong></p>
<p>A large metal door made of silver that sits flush with the walls of the room, the door is also adorned with fancy scrollwork that has been etched into the surface. The door does not have any visible handles and the gaps between the door and the walls are too small to gain leverage with any kind of dungeoneering tool.</p>
<p><em>Note:</em> A key used on the panel will open the door, the Room ID has been left out and will be added when the key is placed in the dungeon.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<hr />
<h2 id="authors-notes">Authors Notes</h2>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>This room originally started as &quot;The Hollow Room&quot; which had a number of oddly shaped holes in the wall, however I thought that keyholes might be more interesting.</p>
<p>I want to give the adventures places to come back to and get &quot;rewards&quot;, setting this up with a future reveal system allows flexibility so keys can be sprinkled into future posts. I also didn't have to come up with a heap of cool &quot;rewards&quot; right away.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<hr />
<h2 id="what-this-all-about">What This All About?</h2>
<p>Check out the <a href="/about/"><strong>About</strong></a> page.</p>
<p>Have any ideas or feedback? Tweet or Direct Message me on <a href="https://www.twitter.com/4A616D6573/"><strong>Twitter</strong></a>.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->« The Sorting Room (F1-R2)<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->The Sleeping Beauty (F1-R4) »<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="room" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A wide rectangle room, on the eastern wall above a small stone platform stands a metal panel displaying countless oddly laid out keyholes.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Sorting Room (F1-R2)</title><link href="https://escapethedungeon.com/posts/F1-R2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Sorting Room (F1-R2)" /><published>2020-04-15T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-04-15T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://escapethedungeon.com/posts/F1-R2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://escapethedungeon.com/posts/F1-R2/"><![CDATA[<p>A long rectangle room with six stone tables flanking either side. Atop the tables sit piles of assorted combat and adventuring equipment in varying condition.</p>
<p>At the far end of the room stands and open door.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/maps/rooms/escapethedungeon-f1-r2-pc.png" alt="The Sorting Room (F1R2)" /></p>
<hr />
<h2 id="game-master">Game Master</h2>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p><img src="/assets/maps/rooms/escapethedungeon-f1-r2-gm.png" alt="The Sorting Room (F1R2)" /></p>
<h1 id="focus-points">Focus Points</h1>
<p><strong>Sorting Tables</strong></p>
<p>Six stone tables piled with equipment, it appears to be loosely sorted into categories. These tables can be searched with an easy inspection check to find salvageable items. Adventurers will be able to find four items.</p>
<p>Use the random table below or your own.</p>
<p><strong>(S) Hidden Stash</strong></p>
<p>Near the north east corner of the room is a hidden stash, denoted with the &quot;S&quot;. An easy inspection check of the room will reveal stone dust on the floor below the stash. An additional easy inspection check will reveal a stone tile in the wall appears to be loose.</p>
<p>The stone tile can be removed with an easy strength check. Inside the hidden stash is a <strong>Jeweled Golden Dagger</strong> and 30 Gold pieces.</p>
<p><strong>Exits</strong></p>
<p>A door stands open at the northern end of the room.</p>
<h1 id="items">Items</h1>
<p><strong>Jeweled Golden Dagger (F1-R2-ITM01)</strong></p>
<p>A curved gold patina dagger incrusted with Ruby gemstones on the hilt and pommel.</p>
<h1 id="random-table">Random Table</h1>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th align="center">Roll</th>
<th align="left">Item</th>
<th align="left">Description</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td align="center">1</td>
<td align="left">Loose Teeth</td>
<td align="left">A handful of loose teeth.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">2</td>
<td align="left">Empty Bottle</td>
<td align="left">An empty bottle.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">3</td>
<td align="left">Edible Ration</td>
<td align="left">A day of rations for one person.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">4</td>
<td align="left">Alien Pendant</td>
<td align="left">A pendant of white stone engraved with an alien symbol.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">5</td>
<td align="left">Plain Clothes</td>
<td align="left">A set of clothes.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">6</td>
<td align="left">Fancy Hat</td>
<td align="left">A fancy hat adorned with a peacock feather.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">7</td>
<td align="left">Unburnt Torch</td>
<td align="left">A unlit torch.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">8</td>
<td align="left">Leather Armor</td>
<td align="left">A set of leather armor.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">9</td>
<td align="left">Rusted Dagger</td>
<td align="left">A dagger with a rusted blade.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">10</td>
<td align="left">Broadsword</td>
<td align="left">A worn Broadsword stained with dried blood.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">11</td>
<td align="left">Spear</td>
<td align="left">A spear with a red ribbon on the pommel.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">12</td>
<td align="left">Wooden Shield</td>
<td align="left">A battered circular wooden shield.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">13</td>
<td align="left">Bow and Quiver of Arrows</td>
<td align="left">A short bow and quiver of 20 arrows.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">14</td>
<td align="left">Blank Sheet of Paper and Charcoal</td>
<td align="left">A large piece of blank paper and a small peice of charcoal.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">15</td>
<td align="left">Crowbar</td>
<td align="left">A metal crowbar.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">16</td>
<td align="left">Scroll of Telekinesis</td>
<td align="left">An old scroll of Telekinesis.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">17</td>
<td align="left">Blank Spell Book</td>
<td align="left">A cheap spell book, unused.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">18</td>
<td align="left">Crossbow and Quiver of Bolts</td>
<td align="left">A crossbow and quiver of 20 bolts.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">19</td>
<td align="left">Standard Healing Potion</td>
<td align="left">A standard healing potion.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="center">20</td>
<td align="left">Immaculate Steel Breastplate</td>
<td align="left">A steel breastplate covered in rust and grime, hiding its perfect condition.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<hr />
<h2 id="authors-notes">Authors Notes</h2>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>The adventurers probably need some starting equipment, if they find this room they will gen an opportunity to get some.</p>
<p>Most of the items in the table were thought up by me, when I couldn't think of anything else I got some items by rolling some random trinkets on <a href="https://donjon.bin.sh/5e/random/#type=trinket">Donjon</a>.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<hr />
<h2 id="what-this-all-about">What This All About?</h2>
<p>Check out the <a href="/about/"><strong>About</strong></a> page.</p>
<p>Have any ideas or feedback? Tweet or Direct Message me on <a href="https://www.twitter.com/4A616D6573/"><strong>Twitter</strong></a>.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->« The Cylinder Cells (F1-R1)<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->The Keyhole Panel (F1-R3) »<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="room" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A long rectangle room with six stone tables flanking either side. Atop the tables sit piles of assorted combat and adventuring equipment in varying condition.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Cylinder Cells (F1-R1)</title><link href="https://escapethedungeon.com/posts/F1-R1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Cylinder Cells (F1-R1)" /><published>2020-04-13T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-04-13T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://escapethedungeon.com/posts/F1-R1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://escapethedungeon.com/posts/F1-R1/"><![CDATA[<p>A large square room filled with floor to ceiling glass cylinders. Each cylinder is filled with a light blue liquid and contains some kind of humanoid form.</p>
<p>In the center of a room is a stone pedestal, top it sits an orb pulsing a dull white glow. Laying on the floor beside the pedestal are four glass vials.</p>
<p>In the middle of each side of the room is a closed wooden door.</p>
<p><img src="/assets/maps/rooms/escapethedungeon-f1-r1-pc.png" alt="The Cylinder Cells (F1R1)" /></p>
<hr />
<h2 id="game-master">Game Master</h2>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<h1 id="boxed-text">Boxed Text</h1>
<p>You and a number of unfamiliar companions awake to the feeling of stale air passing through your nostrils. You look around to find yourself laying naked in a smashed open cylinder, a light blue liquid slowly oozing out onto the floor.</p>
<h1 id="focus-points">Focus Points</h1>
<p><strong>Glowing Orb</strong></p>
<p>A palm sized orb, pulsing a dull white glow. A medium magic check will reveal the orb is operating a reduced capacity but its true function is still unknown.</p>
<p><strong>Glass Vials</strong></p>
<p>Empty thin long glass vials, A very easy inspection check will reveal that these vials socket into a metal ring at the base of the cylinders.</p>
<p><strong>Exits</strong></p>
<p>Above each door is a sign that denotes a direction. &quot;North&quot;, &quot;East&quot;, &quot;South&quot;, and &quot;West&quot; following a clockwise direction. All doors are unlocked.</p>
<h1 id="items">Items</h1>
<p><strong>Glowing Orb (F1-R1-ITM01)</strong></p>
<p>Pulsing a dull white glow, when initially discovered the orb is currently low on charge.</p>
<p>A very hard magic check will reveal that the orb can be recharged by an attuned wielder by expending 10 magic slots. Once charged this orb can hold and emit a single spell within a 20 foot radius as a concentration spell, requiring the attuned wielder to make a spell save every hour the spell is active.</p>
<p>When recharged and active the orb glows bright white.</p>
<p><strong>Preserving Liquid (F1-R1-ITM02)</strong></p>
<p>When consumed it heals for one standard potion, additionally the consumer must make a medium constitution saving throw or fall asleep for 1d4 hours. The properties of this liquid can be identified with a hard magic check.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<hr />
<h2 id="authors-notes">Authors Notes</h2>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>I had to choose somewhere for the adventures to start, waking up in some kind of hibernation tank seemed like a good as place as any. Allows of a variable number of players and provides an initial intrigue.</p>
<p>I decided to include a powerful magic item right out of the gate but make it difficult to use initially, its probably broken as hell but I can come back and refine it if needed.</p>
<p>Also included some healing potions go give the party a leg up.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<hr />
<h2 id="what-this-all-about">What This All About?</h2>
<p>Check out the <a href="/about/"><strong>About</strong></a> page.</p>
<p>Have any ideas or feedback? Tweet or Direct Message me on <a href="https://www.twitter.com/4A616D6573/"><strong>Twitter</strong></a>.<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<p><!-- raw HTML omitted -->The Sorting Room (F1-R2) »<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="room" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A large square room filled with floor to ceiling glass cylinders. Each cylinder is filled with a light blue liquid and contains some kind of humanoid form.]]></summary></entry></feed>